<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<CoffeeHistory>
	
	{  imageName="DancingGoats.jpg" soundName="800.mp3" imageCaption="800 A.D.: Humanity discovers a new energy boost when members of the Galla tribe in Ethiopia notice that their goats begin to prance and dance shortly after eating a certain red berry. The tribesman try it, and get the same stimulating jolt. Soon, ground up coffee beans mixed with animal fat have become a staple part of their diet."/>
	
	{  imageName="ArabTraders.jpg" soundName="1000.mp3" imageCaption="1000 A.D.: Arab traders bring coffee back to their homeland and cultivate the plant for the first time on plantations. They also began to boil the beans, creating a drink they call qahwa (literally, that which prevents sleep)."/>
	
	{  imageName="PayingHomage.jpg" soundName="1453.mp3" imageCaption="1453: Coffee is introduced to Constantinople by Ottoman Turks. The world's first coffee shop, Kiva Han, opens there in 1475. Turkish law makes it legal for a woman to divorce her husband if he fails to provide her with her daily quota of coffee. Coffee is introduced to Constantinople by Ottoman Turks. The world's first coffee shop, Kiva Han, opens there in 1475. Turkish law makes it legal for a woman to divorce her husband if he fails to provide her with her daily quota of coffee. Coffee is introduced to Constantinople by Ottoman Turks. The world's first coffee shop, Kiva Han, opens there in 1475. Turkish law makes it legal for a woman to divorce her husband if he fails to provide her with her daily quota of coffee."/>
	
	{  imageName="PopeClementVIII.jpg" soundName="1600.mp3" imageCaption="1600: Coffee, introduced to the West by Italian traders, grabs attention in high places. In Italy, Pope Clement VIII is urged by his advisers to consider that favorite drink of the Ottoman Empire part of the infidel threat. However, he decides to 'baptize' the beverage instead, making it an acceptable Christian refreshment."/>" 
	
	{  imageName="JohnSmith.jpg" soundName="1607.mp3"  imageCaption="1607: Captain John Smith helps to found the colony of Virginia at Jamestown. It is believed that he introduced coffee to North America."/>
	
	{  imageName="17thCentCoffeeHouse.jpg" soundName="1652.mp3" imageCaption="1652: The first coffeehouse opens in England. Coffee houses multiply and become such popular forums for learned--and not so learned--discussion that they are dubbed 'penny universities'(a penny being the price of a cup of coffee)."/>
	
	{  imageName="CoffeeWars.jpg" soundName="1675.mp3" imageCaption="1675: The Turkish Army surrounds Vienna, Austria. Franz Georg Kolschitzky, a Viennese who had lived in Turkey, slips through the enemy lines to lead relief forces to the city. The fleeing Turks leave behind sacks of 'dry black fodder' that Kolschitzky recognizes as coffee. He claims it as his reward for saving Vienna and opens central Europe's first coffee house."/>
	
	{  imageName="LouisXVI.jpg" soundName="1713.mp3" imageCaption="1713: The Dutch unwittingly provide Louis XIV of France with a coffee bush when a French naval officer  steals a seedling and transports it to Martinique, a French island colony in the West Indies. This one plant's descendants will literally provide the seeds of the entire Western coffee industry, for within 50 years there are 19 million coffee trees on Martinique. Eventually, 90 percent of the world's coffee will be traced back to this one stolen seedling."/>
	
	{  imageName="BrazilianLtCol.jpg" soundName="1727.mp3" imageCaption="1727: The Brazilian coffee industry gets its start when Lieutenant colonel Francisco de Melo Palheta strikes up a secret liaison with the wife of French Guiana's governor. Although France guarded its New World coffee plantations to prevent cultivation from spreading, the lady surreptitiously supplies Palheta with cuttings and fertile seeds of coffee. The Brazilian coffee industry gets its start when Lieutenant colonel Francisco de Melo Palheta strikes up a secret liaison with the wife of French Guiana's governor. Although France guarded its New World coffee plantations to prevent cultivation from spreading, the lady surreptitiously supplies Palheta with cuttings and fertile seeds of coffee."/>

</CoffeeHistory>